♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 9=
(Barrier)
(On the day of the wedding,
we'll meet at Fengcheng Station.)
(Miss Jiang, forgive me.)
(I had to do it.)
(Because)
(after the Rongqing Troupe
was slaughtered, I became all alone,)
(lingering in this world,)
(To Miss Jiang)
only for using Xu Fan's blood
to avenge the Rongqing Troupe.
(And the wedding
is the only chance I can kill him.)
Young Marshal.
The troops are all ready.
Send troops to protect Chun'er.
The Governor Mansion is heavily guarded.
We still can't let our guard down.
Yes!
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
(Chang'an)
♪Scars all over me♪
I won't let anyone
control my life again.
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
Bow to heaven and earth.
(I know I might not survive this.)
(It's shameful to do so,
but I have to ask you two favors.)
(After I die, if possible,)
- (please bury my corpse with Master's.)
- Bow to each other.
(Also, please help me find Shitou.)
(I don't seek to reunite with him.)
- (I want to know if he is living well.)
- Good!
Good!
(Take care.)
Governor!
Why are you here?
Where is Chun'er?
This is my only chance to kill Xu Fan.
You assassinated Governor in public.
Are you seeking death?
I know I committed a crime.
But I must get rid of him
to avenge Master
and everyone in the Rongqing Troupe.
Young Marshal.
Kill the murderer to avenge Governor!
Insolent!
Now, I am in charge here.
- You!
- Today, I have to protect Rong Xiaonan!
Xu You'an, are you
rebelling against Governor?
What?
The position of Governor is always mine.
♪Candle by the west window♪
Let him go.
♪Ending in nothingness♪
♪I ask why♪
Rong Xiaonan.
You can survive today
not because you are lucky,
but because on such a fine day,
I don't want to stain my hands.
Get lost.
♪No one comes to meet me♪
♪Candle by the west window♪
(You resemble Zhuzi so much.)
(I will spare your life)
(as a way to make amends for the regret
of not being able to save Zhuzi.)
♪A handful of earth♪
♪The world's last gamble♪
♪Sighing at the late hour♪
Quick makeup change!
♪Dream of a big garden♪
♪Under the plum tree♪
Keep your breathing steadier
at the high notes.
Yes, Master.
I'll hold it steady.
Performing is like living.
To reach the heights,
you must first go low.
♪Without entering the garden♪
♪How can I know the beauty of spring♪
♪To express the feelings in dreams♪
Fan.
Remember, your poses
must be sharp, clean,
and beautiful.
Okay.
♪Chunxiang, lead the way♪
- Look, Mr. Rong is coming out!
- Mr. Rong is coming out!
- Mr. Rong!
- Good!
Mr. Rong!
(Rongqing Troupe)
Master,
my fellows,
now that I've avenged the great grudge,
why do I feel no sense of relief?
When I slacked off in practice,
you said I revealed a hint of cunning.
You were right.
You often said,
an actor must follow nine-fold rules.
But for revenge,
I deceived and used Chun'er.
I became the person I despise the most.
I'm sinking deeper into schemes.
(Tomb of respected master, Rong Huaiqiu)
Master, do you still
acknowledge me as your disciple?
(Tomb of respected master, Rong Huaiqiu)
(Master.)
(I can't stay in Fengcheng anymore.)
(I couldn't revive the Rongqing Troupe.)
(Just consider it
as me skipping class again.)
(Tomb of respected master, Rong Huaiqiu)
(Governor Mansion)
Except me, no one can enter this room.
Yes!
Young...
Governor,
there's a guest here.
(Du Xiaolin,
President of Xiaosheng Society)
Young Marshal Xu,
do you know who I am?
As long as you know who I am.
Before, the Old Governor used artifacts
to trade with us for advanced weapons.
If you can provide the items,
the deal continues,
and all grudges will be wiped clean.
Provide you the items,
and the deal is done.
Give me the Jade Buddha Head
and kingfisher phoenix crown.
The ship with weapons
will arrive at the port soon.
After all,
Fengcheng Port has long been ours.
See the guest out.
Please.
Darn it! How dare he negotiate terms!
Governor,
I'll take men and wipe him out.
I've just taken power,
it's not stable yet.
Send someone to tail them
and wipe them all out
after investigation.
Yes!
Father, I was wrong.
Master.
Father!
Someone's dead!
The Master is dead!
Help!
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪